所以我们已经看到了一个 gen server 的例子
so we've seen one example of a gen server
我们现在想向您展示一个
we'd like to now show you a
运行中的 gen 服务器的不同示例
different example of a gen server in action
特别是
in particular
我们可以使用 nit 和处理信息回调函数
we can use the nit and handle info callback functions
便于安排定期工作
to make it easy to schedule periodic work
记得前段时间我们研究了传感器的路线
remember a while back we worked on a sensor's route
现在该路由a同步获得三个
now that route a synchronously gets three
快照图像
snapshot images
和bigfoot当前的gps位置
and bigfoot's current gps location
即使api同时请求一个
and even though the api request one concurrently
这样我们就可以在一秒钟内得到所有的结果
so that we get all the results in just one second
这个传感器数据并不会经常改变
this sensor data it doesn't really change very often
所以我们打这些api没有意义
so there's no sense in us hitting these apis
每次我们想要获取传感器请求时
every time we want to get a request for sensors
反而
instead
我们想兑现结果并刷新现金
we want to cash the results and refresh the cash
每隔一小时
every hour
所以要做到这一点，我们将需要另一个 gen 服务器
so to do that we're going to need another gen server
所以我们已经开始写了
so we've gone ahead and started to write
传感器服务器
a sensor server
让我们来看看
let's walk through it
这是一个世代服务器
it's a gen server
我们在那里有 use gen server 行
we have the use gen server line right there
然后就我们的客户端界面而言，我们有一个
and then in terms of our client interface we've got a
刚刚启动 gen 服务器的 start 函数
start function that just starts the gen server
我们给它起了个名字
and we gave it a name
就像我们对其他一代服务器所做的那样
just like we did with our other gen server
这个名字是传感器服务器
this one's name is sensor server
我们不是有获取传感器数据的功能吗
didn't we have a get sensor data function
那是一个电话，因为一个电话信息
that is a call since a call message
它将传感器数据传送到服务器
it's get sensor data over to the server
然后就我们的服务器回调而言，我们有我们的
then in terms of our server callbacks we have our
尼特函数
nit function
请记住，它会被自动调用
remember that gets called automatically by the
启动功能
start function
现在开始功能
now the start function
它的第二个参数是这个空地图
its 2nd argument is this empty map
但我们只是忽略它作为状态的一部分
but we just ignore that as part of the state
因为我们想要做的
because what we want to do instead
运行任务以获取传感器数据
is run the tasks to get the sensor data
并让它成为我们的初始状态
and have that be our initial state
从针织物返回
that gets returned from a knit
所以当这个过程开始时
so when the process starts
它立即运行任务以获取此数据
it immediately runs the tasks to get this data
那么这里的这个函数是做什么的
so what does this function here do
好吧，这正是我们在处理程序中所拥有的
well it's just what we had in our handler
它运行任务以获取偏执者的位置
it runs the task to get bigots location
以及获取快照图像的任务
and the task to get the snapshot images
然后它返回一个地图
and then it returns a map
我们这次使用地图
we use the map this time
快照的键有一个快照列表
the key of snapshots has a list of snapshots
位置键有
a key of location has
偏执狂的位置
bigots location
然后那个返回映射成为我们的初始状态
and then that return map becomes our initial state
我们从针织品中返回
which we return from a knit
然后有一个把手
then there's a handle
调用处理获取的函数子句
call function clause that handles to get
传感器数据消息
sensor data message
它只是回复状态
and it just replies with the state
这就是我们发回给客户的内容
that's what we send back to the client
然后是我们想要重现的状态
and then the state we want to recurs with
是同一个状态
is that same state
结果已经兑现
and the results are already in the cash
所以当客户端调用获取传感器数据时
so when the client calls get sensor data
它只是直接来自现金
it just comes straight out of the cash
让我们快速旋转一下
let's give it a quick spin and ex
启动我们的传感器服务器
fire up our sensor server
好吧，我们看到了
all right we see that
它正在运行任务以获取传感器数据
it's running the task to get the sensor data
所以我们的现金都被加热了
so our cash is all warmed up
现在如果我们打电话给服务
now if we call service
传感器服务器
sensor server
获取传感器数据
get sensor data
好吧，它立即返回
well it returns immediately
与位置
with the location
以及已经在现金中的快照
and the snapshots that are already in the cash
现在您可能会注意到我们的快照图像
now you might notice that our snapshot image
文件名有点不同
file names are a little different
我们改变了视频
we've changed the video
cam 分配随机数到每个的末尾
cam to assign random numbers to the end of each
文件名而已
file name just
所以我们可以展示即将到来的兑现行为
so we can demonstrate the upcoming cashing behavior
我们在视频摄像头模块中完成了这项工作
we did that over in the video cam module
你注意到我们只是添加了一个破折号然后我们使用
you notice we just added a dash and then we use
再次统一函数
that rand uniform function again
获取 1 到 1000 之间的随机数
to get a random number between one and 1000
所以现在我们知道这是可行的，我们可以改变
so now that we know that this works we can change
我们在处理程序中的传感器行
our sensor row in handler
ex 实际使用我们的 gen 服务器
ex to actually use our gen server
是的，我们现在可以摆脱这一切
yeah we can get rid of all this now
因为那在我们的 gen 服务器中
because that's in our gen server
我们只会说传感器数据
and we'll just say sensor data
等于传感器服务器
equals sensor server
获取传感器数据
get sensor data
然后我们将检查它
and then we'll just inspect it
使其成为响应主体
to make it the response body
这就是我们的传感器服务器当前的工作方式
so here's how our sensor server currently works
当调用 start 函数时
when the start function is invoked
它回调 nit 函数
it calls back to the nit function
从外部 API 获取传感器数据
which fetches the sensor data from external apis
并将数据缓存为进程资产
and caches the data as the process estate
然后当客户端调用获取传感器数据函数时
then when a client invokes the get sensor data function
它只是返回现金中的任何数据
it simply returns whatever data is in the cash
虽然在幕后
behind the scenes though
每小时我们希望现金刷新一次
every hour we want the cash to refresh with
新的传感器数据
new sensor data
但是传感器服务器如何知道刷新其现金
but how will the sensor server know to refresh its cash
进程知道做某事的唯一方法
well the only way a process knows to do something
是通过接收消息
is by receiving a message
所以我们将拥有传感器服务器
so we'll have the sensor server
向自己发送一条刷新的消息
send a refreshed message to itself
每小时这里是它的工作方式
every hour here's how it will work
nit 回调函数会做两件事
the nit callback function will do two things
获取和
fetch and
从外部 api 兑现初始传感器数据
cash the initial sensor data from the external apis
然后安排一条刷新消息到
and then schedule a refresh message to
传感器服务器 未来 60 分钟
sensor server 60min in the future
一小时后，该消息被发送
an hour later that message is then sent
它由句柄信息回调函数处理
it's handled by the handle info callback function
并且现金已更新
and the cash is updated
但一个小时后
but an hour from now
服务器如何知道再次刷新其现金
how does the server know to refresh its cash again
好吧，每次处理信息处理刷新消息
well every time handle info handles the refresh message
它将安排下一个要发送的刷新消息
it will schedule the next refresh message to be sent
未来 60 分钟
60min in the future
并以这种方式
and in this way
刷新消息被发送到传感器服务器
a refresh message is sent to the sensor server
现在每小时刷新一次现金是
every hour now refreshing the cash every hour is
如果这合理
reasonable if this
在生产环境中运行
were running in a production environment
但我们认为你不想等那么久
but we don't think you want to wait around that long
看到它在行动
to see it in action
所以我们在这个模块中实际上只需要 5 秒
so we'll actually make it only 5 seconds in this module
在 nit 回调函数中
in the nit callback function
让我们安排第一个
let's schedule the first
刷新要发送的消息，我们会做对的
refresh message to be sent and we'll do it right
在我们有了初始状态之后
after we have our initial state
我们将使用一个新功能
and we're going to use a new function
它在流程模块中，并且调用了该函数
it's in the process module and the function is called
发送后啊哈
send after aha
它需要三个参数
and it takes three arguments
第一个是
the first one is the
我们要将消息发送到的 pid
pid that we want to send the message to
在这种情况下将是我们自己
in this case is going to be ourself
所以我们只需要调用 self
so we're just going to call self
然后消息
then the message
将要刷新
is going to be refresh
然后第三个参数是我们要等待多长时间
and then the third argument is how long we want to wait
直到我们发送该消息
until we send that message
这是一个以毫秒为单位的时间
and it's a time expressed in milliseconds
但不是做数学来达到 5 秒
but rather than doing the math to get to 5 seconds
我将使用早期计时器模块
I'm going to use the early timer module
还有一个
and there's a
名为 seconds 的函数，我们只传递它 5
function called seconds and we just pass it five
然后那会让我们回来
and then that'll give us back
毫秒数
the number of milliseconds
所以发送后功能将发送
so the send after function is going to send
这个消息给这个进程
this message to this process
在这个小毫秒之后
after this mini milliseconds
现在这条消息是原始消息或普通消息
now this message is a raw or plain message
这既不是电话也不是演员
it's neither a call or a cast
并记住
and remember
所有未使用 call 或 cast 发送的消息
all messages that aren't sent using call or cast
会被把手捡起来
are going to be picked up by the handle
信息回调函数
info callback function
所以我们需要定义其中之一
so we need to define one of those
我就在这里做
I'll just do it right here
这是句柄信息
it's handle info
消息正在刷新
the message is refresh
然后第二个参数总是状态
and then the second argument is always the state
我们不会使用
which we're not going to use
所以我会在那里使用下划线
so I'll use an underscore there
然后我将开始打印
and then I'm just going to start by printing out
清爽
refreshing
现金
the cash
然后刷新现金
and then to refresh the cash
我们需要运行那个函数
we need to run that function
运行任务获取中心数据
run task to get center data
然后我们将其分配给新状态
and then we'll just assign that to new state
那将是我们的新现金
that'll be our new cash
然后我们将其作为元组返回
and then we return that as a tuple
无回复
no reply
新状态
new state
好的，这样可以处理消息
okay so that handles the message
现在我们的邮箱是空的
and now our mailbox would be empty
那么服务器如何知道刷新其现金
so then how will the server know to refresh its cash in
下一个小时
the next hour
刷新现金后
well after refreshing the cash
我们需要安排下一条刷新消息
we need to schedule the next refresh message
是的，我只是要抓住这个
yeah I'm just going to grab this
因为我们需要做同样的事情
because we're going to need to do the same thing
然后我们就把它放在这里
and then we're just going to put it right here
在我们计算出新的状态之后
after we calculate the new state
虽然我们要安排下一条刷新消息
while we're going to schedule the next refresh message
未来5秒
for 5 seconds in the future
现在我只是把它复制下来
now I just copied that down
所以我们这里有一些重复
so we've got some duplication here
让我们在这里编写一个快速函数来清理它
let's clean it up by writing a quick function here
它只是一个私人功能
it'll just be a private function
我们称之为计划刷新
and we'll call it schedule refresh
然后我们把它放在里面
and then we'll just put this inside of there
然后在这条线上我们可以调用 schedule refresh
and then on this line we can call schedule refresh
和这里一样
and the same up here
然后让它更容易改变
and then to make it easier to change
实际间隔
the actual interval
我们可以把这个时间
we could put this time
在模块属性中，让我们继续执行此操作
in a module attribute so let's go ahead and do that
我将在刷新间隔调用模块属性
I'll call the module attribute at refresh interval
然后在这里的顶部
and then up at the top here
我们将其定义为刷新间隔
we'll just define it as at refresh interval
然后在我们的例子中是 5 秒
and then it'll be 5 seconds in our case
但如果你在生产中，你会使用一些东西
but if you were in production you would use something
像计时器点
like timer dot
分钟
minutes
好的，让我们在新的修复会话中试一试
okay let's give this a spin in a new fix session
我们启动我们的传感器服务器
we start up our sensor server
5秒后我们看到它是
and after 5 seconds we see that it's
刷新现金和
refreshing the cash and
运行任务以获取传感器数据
running the task to get the sensor data
哦，又过了 5 秒，它又出现了，所以
oh there it went again after another 5 seconds so
每 5 秒刷新一次现金
every 5 seconds it's refreshing the cash
所以现在让我们继续获取传感器 dana
so now let's go ahead and get the sensor dana
好吧，它会返回
well it returns it back
注意这里我们有快照三三十一
notice here that we've got snapshot three thirty one
在后台
and in the background
它仍然每 5 秒刷新一次现金
it's still refreshing the cash every 5 seconds
所以如果我们再次得到它
so if we get it again
现在改成四八十四
now this is changed to four eighty four
等等
and so on
所以在幕后
so behind the scenes
服务器还在
the server still
负责定期更新现金
takes care of updating the cash on a periodic interval
我们希望这能让你思考
we hope this gets you thinking about
生成服务器的其他有趣用例
other interesting use cases for a gen server
不仅仅是简单地存储状态
beyond just simply storing state